So it's quite an adventure that we had at the frontier of what's capable with Llms today, solving a
오늘날의 Lms는 정말 대단한 모험이었습니다 세계
particular problem that required world knowledge and to take you through what we saw from the performance
지식이 필요한 문제를 해결했고 지난 시간에 살펴본 성능을 다시
of everything as a reminder from last time we started.
한번 보여드릴게요
Well, actually, we started with the random model, but we'll forget about that because that was silly.
사실 무작위 모델로 시작했지만 바보 같았으니 잊어버리기로 하죠
We're proper first starting point was a constant model that just predicted an average number.
우선 상수 모델로 평균 수치를 예측했어요
We obviously were able to do better, but not that much better.
더 잘할 수 있었지만 그렇게 많이는 아니었어요
With a model that used feature engineering, you may have improved on that with better features.
기능 공학 모델을 사용하면 더 나은 기능으로 향상시킬 수 있어요
Um, but our best one was a random forest model based on a not a bag of words.
하지만 제일 좋았던 건 아무 말이나 갖다 붙인 숲속 모델이었어요
A word to vec vectorized.
벡터라이즈에게 전해요
Uh, look at the prompts with 400 dimensional vectors.
400차원 벡터가 있는 프롬프트 좀 보세요
And that brought our error.
그게 우리의 실수를 가져왔죠
The average difference between the prediction and the actual price of a product based on its description
설명에 근거한 제품의 예측과 실제 가격 사이의 평균 차이는 400,000개의
down to $97 being after being trained on 400,000 example data points.
예시 데이터 포인트에 대해 훈련된 후의 97달러까지로 줄어들죠
We then, uh, unveiled the human today.
오늘 그 인간을 공개했어요
That was our first model.
그게 첫 번째 모델이었어요
Uh, and the human got 127 in terms of error.
참가자는 오차로 127점을 받았어요
So you'll see, I was able to, uh, at least do better than the very primitive feature engineering.
그래서 제가 적어도 원시적인 기능 공학보다는 잘 만들 수 있었어요
And at least I did better than than constant.
꾸준한 것보다는 나았네요
I think I wouldn't have, uh, I might not have included the whole result if I hadn't done better than
제가 상수보다 잘하지 않았다면 전체 결과를 포함하지
a constant number.
않았을 거예요
Uh, but, uh, obviously, uh, the next, uh, Claude clearly, uh, did significantly better than
하지만 다음 클로드는 저보다 훨씬 잘했어요
me.
클로드는 아무 숲이나 숲과 아주 비슷했어요 아주 비슷했죠
And again, one has to bear in mind, Claude is doing this without seeing any training data.
다시 한번 명심해야 할 점은 클로드는 훈련 데이터를 보지 않고 이걸 하고 있다는 거죠
It's just purely based on its world knowledge.
순전히 세계 지식에 근거한 거예요
And then being given this product.
이 제품을 받았을 때요
And I can tell you from bitter personal experience that that is a challenging task.
씁쓸한 개인적인 경험으로 말씀드리자면 정말 어려운 작업이에요
But GPT four mini did better and got down to an $80 error, and GPT four did even better yet and brought
GPT 4 미니는 더 잘해서 80달러까지 낮췄습니다 GPT 4 미니는 더 잘해서
it down to $76 in terms of the difference.
76달러까지 낮췄죠
So it shows you that out of the box, working with frontier models and APIs, you can build solutions
프론티어 모델과 API를 이용해 문제 해결법을 구축할 수 있습니다
to problems, even problems which feel like they are regression problems.
퇴행 문제처럼 보이는 문제도요
They're not.
아니에요
They're numerical problems.
숫자 문제라고요
They don't necessarily naturally sound like they should be ones where just text completion will be able
텍스트만 완성하면 해결될 것 같은 자연적인 소리는 아니에요
But even given that kind of problem still out of the box, GPT four mini is able to outperform a random
하지만 그런 문제에도 불구하고 GPT 4 미니는 임의의 숲 모델을 능가할 수 있습니다 400,000개의
forest model, a traditional machine learning model with 400,000 training data points.
훈련 데이터 포인트가 있는 전통적인 머신 러닝 모델이죠
So it just goes to show you how powerful these models are and how they can be applied to so many types
이런 모델들이 얼마나 강력한지 보여줍니다 다양한 유형의 상업적 문제에 어떻게 적용할
of commercial problem.
수 있는지도요
But with that, we can now finally move on to the world of training.
하지만 이제 드디어 훈련의 세계로 넘어갈 수 있겠네요
The next subject is going to be about how we take this further, by fine tuning a frontier model to
다음 주제는 어떻게 발전시키느냐입니다 개척 시대 모델을 세밀하게 조정해서
take what it's got and do better with training examples.
훈련 예시를 더 잘 활용하는 거죠
The thing that it hasn't had so far.
지금까지 없었던 거요
So that is a big and exciting topic.
아주 크고 흥미로운 주제죠
It will then complete this week before next week.
다음 주 전에 완성될 거예요
We take it to a whole different world where we try and fine tune our own open source model to see if
완전히 다른 세계로 가져가서 오픈 소스 모델을 세밀하게 조정해 경쟁할 수 있는지 봅니다
we can compete, bearing in mind that we'll be dealing with something with massively fewer parameters.
매개 변수가 아주 적은 걸 다루게 될 거라는 걸 염두에 두고요
So a very different world.
완전히 다른 세상이죠
And to see whether or not we have a hope of beating traditional machine learning or frontier models.
전통적인 머신 러닝이나 선구적 모델을 이길 수 있을지 확인해 보죠
Lots to be excited about.
기대할 게 많아요
But first, I will see you tomorrow for fine tuning.
하지만 먼저 내일 다시 만나서 조율을 하죠